Lewis Nathaniel Chase Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General File, 1836-1941 (Box 34-162)
  - Turner, W. J., 1921-1939
  - Tuttle, Lelia Judson, 1933-1938
  - Tynan, Katherine, 1917
  - Tyranny of Tears, undated
  - “U” miscellaneous
    - Correspondence, 1912-1915, 1930, 1937-1938
    - Miscellany, 1905, 1912, undated
    - Newspaper clippings, 1928
  - U. D. C., Woodrow Wilson Chapter, 1937
  - Underhill, John Garrett, 1923
  - Union College, Schenectady, N.Y., 1927-1936, (4 folders)
  - United Literary Press, 1904-1905 (Box 150)
  - Unitarianism, 1935
  - USA postal cards, undated
  - Universities
    - A-B, 1917-1937, (6 folders)
    - C-I, 1903-1907, 1917-1937, (12 folders) (Box 151)
    - I-L, 1904-1914, 1920, undated, (8 folders) (Box 152)
    - L-N, 1906-1912, 1921-1929, 1937, (8 folders) (Box 153)
    - N-R, 1906, 1916-1940, (9 folders) (Box 154)
    - R, 1917-1920, (4 folders) (Box 155)
    - R-W, 1916-1937, (11 folders) (Box 156)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1917, 1931, 1937-1939, undated
  - Utopian fallacy, 1923
  - “V” miscellaneous (Box 157)
    - Correspondence, 1907-1914, 1928-1940
    - Miscellany, 1912, 1933, undated
    - Newspaper clippings, 1923, 1936-1937
  - Vacuum cleaners, 1910-1912, undated
  - Vagabond voyage, 1915-1924
  - Valise, 1913
  - Van Brugh, John, 1903, undated
  - Vandenburgh, John, 1895-1897
  - Vadergrift, F. B., 1928
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1932, 1940-1941
  - Van Dyke, Henry, 1908, 1927-1936
  - Vansittart, Robert, 1927-1941
  - Van Winkle, Wallace T., 1908-1909
  - Veblen, Thorstein, 1918
  - Vers-de-societe, 1913
  - Verses by Lewis Chase, 1904-1905, undated, (2 folders)
  - Veterans, 1936
  - Viereck, George Sylvester, 1932
  - Village community, 1926 (Box 158)
  - Village Drama Society, 1922-1929
  - Vines, Sherard, 1928
  - Vivekanada, Swami, undated
  - Valkeapaa, Peter and Louise, 1933-1939
  - Vollmer, Lula, 1924
  - Voorhis, Sheldon, 1932-1941
  - “W” miscellaneous
    - Correspondence, 1907-1913, 1926-1941
    - Miscellany, 1912-1914, 1930-1936
    - Newspaper clippings, 1905, 1928-1939
  - Waddell, Helen, 1935-1936
  - Wainger, Bertrand, 1930
  - Wakefield, Elisabeth Adams, 1933-1940
  - Walden, Minnie Jackson, 1932-1938
  - Waley, Arthur, 1928
  - Walker, Arthur, 1910-1913, (2 folders)
  - Walker, Frederick, undated
  - Walker, Thomas, 1928
  - Wallace, Charles William, 1914 (Box 159)
  - Wallace, Edna K., 1917-1920
  - Wallas, Graham, 1921, 1926
  - Waller, Edmund, 1927
  - Walpole, Horace, 1937-1940
  - Walpole, Hugh, 1912, 1936
  - Wannamaker, W. H., 1931
  - War clippings, 1915
  - War, cause of, 1932
  - War poetry, undated
  - Ward, A. C., 1928-1931
  - Ward, Frank A. (family), 1919-1935
  - Ward, Lydia Avery Coonley, 1896, 1916-1924
  - Warner, F. L., undated
  - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1928-1931
  - Washburn, Abbie Chase, undated
  - Washington, D.C., 1931-1938
  - Wasson, Julia, 1928-1937
  - Watson, James W., undated
  - Watson, William, 1928-1935
  - Wearne, undated
  - Weaving, Willoughby, 1921
  - Webb, Mary, 1928, 1939
  - Webster, John, 1928, 1940
  - Weed, Inis H., 1911-1919
  - Wellesley, Dorothy, 1936-1939
  - Wellock, Wilfred, 1916
  - Wells, H. G., 1926, 1934
  - Wells, H. G., in France, 1912
  - Wells, Ralph C., 1923
  - Weltner, Mrs. Charles E., 1936-1940
  - Wendell, Barrett, 1908
  - Wendt, A. T., 1929
  - Wen Yu Hui, 1921-1922
  - Westbrook, Mrs. J. D., 1913
  - Westminster Abbey, 1903
  - Westminster Gazette, 1908-1912
  - Whale, H. L., 1914
  - Wharton, Edith, 1914, 1934-1937
  - Wheeler, Joseph L., 1936
  - Wheelock, Dolly, 1907, 1912, 1930-1937
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1913, 1931
  - Wheelwright, John, 1919 (Box 160)
  - Where to spend the summer, 1920
  - Whistler, Rex, 1937
  - White, Anna M., undated
  - White, A. E., 1921
  - White, Newman I., 1940
  - White, Owen P., 1925
  - White, T. W., 1935, undated
  - L & W Whitehead, Ltd., 1910-1912
  - Whitehead, Captain C. (family), 1933-1940
  - Whitehead, F. C., 1928, undated
  - Whiteside, Mary Brent, 1933
  - Whitlock, Brand, undated
  - Whitridge, Arnold, 1928
  - Who's Who, 1905, 1911-1937, (2 folders)
  - Wiggam, Lionel, 1936
  - Wilbur, Mary, 1935-1941
  - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler, 1919
  - Wilde, Oscar, 1903-1912, 1938-1940
  - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Va., 1929
  - William Smith College, Geneva, N.Y., 1918
  - Williams, Alfred, 1926
  - Williams, Charles, 1930-1939
  - Williams, Harold, 1933
  - Williams, L. Henderson, 1911-1912
  - Williams, Oscar, 1939-1940
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1934-1940
  - Willis, J. C., 1910
  - Willis, Penelope, 1930
  - Wilner, 1909
  - Wilson, Francis, 1934-1937 (Box 161)
  - Wilson, J. Dover, 1916-1918, 1937-1938, 1944
  - Wilson, John, undated
  - Wilson, Rathmell, 1913
  - Wimbledon, 1911
  - Wimmer, W. J., 1915
  - Wimsatt, Genevieve, 1934-1939
  - Anne, Countess of Winchelsea, 1928
  - Winter, Robert, 1925
  - Witherspoon, Charles, 1932-1935
  - Wolf children, undated
  - Wolfe, Humbert, 1926-1930, 1939-1940
  - Wollstonecraft, Mary and William Godwin, 1927
  - Wolfe, Thomas, 1935-1940
  - Women, 1920-1928
  - Women writers, 1913
  - Women's clubs, 1907-1910, 1929, (2 folders)
  - Women's Educational and Industrial Union, 1914
  - Women's Rest Tour Association, 1907-1914
  - Wong, J. Quincey, 1924-1925
  - Wood, Clement, 1936
  - Woodberry, George Edward, 1899, 1917, 1925
  - Woods, Charles, 1926, 1934
  - Woods, Mrs. Henry, 1936
  - Woods, George Benjamin, 1929
  - Woods, Margaret L., 1913-1921
  - Woolf, Virginia, 1925-1941
  - Words, 1926-1929
  - World War I, 1914-1918, 1928
  - Worthington, Charles Lloyd, 1931
  - Wotton, Henry, 1908
  - Wright, George H., 1933
  - Writer's Club, 1912 (Box 162)
  - Wroth, Lawrence C., 1936-1939
  - Wurdemann, Audrey, 1937-1940
  - Wylie, Elinor, 1928-1933
  - Wynn, William T., 1933
  - Yeats, William Butler, 1906, 1923-1941
  - Young, Barbara, 1935-1939
  - Zaturenska, Marya, 1937
  - Zola, 1923, 1940
- Family Correspondence, 1883-1941 (Box 163-182)
  Correspondence of Lewis Nathaniel Chase, Pearl-Adell Chase, and other family members. Organized into three files: letters from Lewis Chase's parents and other family members, letters from Lewis Chase and Pearl-Adell Chase to members of his family, and correspondence of other members of the Chase family.
  No arrangement within the files, but described according to the chronological spans within folders.
  - Chase, Lewis Nathaniel (Box 163)
    - Letters from home
      - 1895-1908, (9 folders)
      - 1906-1911, (8 folders) (Box 164)
      - 1912-1914, (4 folders) (Box 165)
      - 1914-1928, undated, (13 folders) (Box 166)
    - Letters to home (Box 167)
      - 1893-1902, (4 folders)
      - 1903-1910, (9 folders) (Box 168)
      - 1911-1915, (6 folders) (Box 169)
      - 1915-1920, (7 folders) (Box 170)
      - 1921-1929, (10 folders) (Box 171)
  - Chase, Lewis Nathaniel Chase and Pearl-Adell (Box 172)
    - 1903-1938, (7 folders)
    - 1911-1941, (8 folders) (Box 173)
    - 1906-1940, (8 folders) (Box 174)
    - 1897-1937, (19 folders) (Box 175)
    - 1908-1941, (7 folders) (Box 176)
    - 1883-1940, (6 folders) (Box 177)
    - 1906-1940, (7 folders) (Box 178)
    - 1895-1928, (2 folders) (Box 179)
    - 1899-1928, (4 folders) (Box 180)
    - 1907-1929, (5 folders) (Box 181)
    - 1886-1937, (10 folders) (Box 182)
- Miscellany, 1892-1939 (Box 183-199)
  Biographical and diary material, lecture notes, press clippings, printed matter, and other papers relating to Nathaniel Lewis Chase.
  No arrangement but described according to the chronological spans within folders.
  - 1901-1939, (11 folders) (Box 183)
  - 1892-1924, (13 folders) (Box 184)
  - 1910, (12 folders) (Box 185)
  - 1910-1912, (17 folders) (Box 186)
  - 1912-1924, (4 folders) (Box 187)
  - 1911-1914, (15 folders) (Box 188)
  - 1912-1914, (8 folders) (Box 189)
  - 1914-1925, (10 folders) (Box 190)
  - 1924-1930, (13 folders) (Box 191)
  - 1897-1938, (18 folders) (Box 192)
  - 1900-1937, (10 folders) (Box 193)
  - 1905-1911, (7 folders) (Box 194)
  - 1937, (5 folders) (Box 195)
  - 1902-1934, undated, (17 folders) (Box 196)
  - 1903-1939, (18 folders) (Box 197)
  - 1903-1937, (15 folders) (Box 198)
  - 1908-1911, (4 folders) (Box 199)
- Other Family Members, 1896-1941 (Box 200-215)
  Files relating to Pearl-Adell Chase and Emma Chase, including correspondence, diaries, notes, writings, and other family material.
  No arrangement within the two files but described according to the chronological spans within folders.
  - Chase, Pearl-Adell (Box 200)
    - 1911-1929, (9 folders)
    - 1914-1916, (5 folders) (Box 201)
    - 1907-1915, (7 folders) (Box 202)
    - 1908-1932, (16 folders) (Box 203)
    - 1896-1931, (9 folders) (Box 204)
    - 1907-1927, (4 folders) (Box 205)
    - 1915, undated (Box 206)
  - Chase, Emma (Box 207)
    - 1921-1939, (6 folders)
    - 1918-1938, (5 folders) (Box 208)
    - 1926-1940, (6 folders) (Box 209)
    - 1916-1941, (4 folders) (Box 210)
    - 1923-1941, (11 folders) (Box 211)
    - 1931-1939, (8 folders) (Box 212)
    - 1913-1941, (9 folders) (Box 213)
    - 1925-1940, (11 folders) (Box 214)
    - 1924-1941, (26 folders) (Box 215)
- China, 1921-1941 (Box 216-223)
  Letters to and from Chinese friends and acquaintances, writings and clippings on China, notes, student papers, and related matter.
  No arrangement.
  - 1919-1941, (21 folders) (Box 216)
  - 1911-1940, (24 folders) (Box 217)
  - 1921-1936, (14 folders) (Box 218)
  - 1922-1940, (12 folders) (Box 219)
  - 1915-1935, (18 folders) (Box 220)
  - 1915-1935, (19 folders) (Box 221)
  - 1916-1934, (13 folders) (Box 222)
  - 1921-1940, (4 folders) (Box 223)
- Addition, 1931 (Box 224)
  Poetry.
  - Poems, 1931, undated (Box 224)